Set up or anything like that.
Well, actually, I a wonderful moderator.
Can you see the chat?
Yes, I have put two links in there.
As our wonderful moderator,
can you be in charge of inviting
new people in and saying,
these are the links we're working on
and I will put in a note for you
saying, hi, wonderful new person.
Please register.
Well, please
get a Wikipedia account.
Have you Glenn?
Have you gotten a Wikipedia account?
I'm going to have to unearth it.
I was meant to come to your workshop
in Toronto last year,
but my flight was a little delayed.
So happy to be here this time
around. Yay!
So we have those explaining to Lyle.
We have two two goals
out of this workshop.
One is force you guys to be Wikipedia
editors forevermore
because it's really important
and I will keep going on to that.
So the first link is the one
to our electronic literature group.
And I can we will talk you through that.
First I will have you share your screen.
So you see how to do this.
If you can take people aside to do that.
The second is on face blind.
And we took a lot of pictures in Toronto
and I have no idea who people are still.
So I kind of go through and people
are going to go, oh, this is this person.
And what I may end up doing is putting
some of these on the discord going high.
Who are these people?
That's actually a good idea.
This time
I will start doing that this evening.
Recording this one.
Sure.
Why not?
So I kind of know how to do the wiki.
I am now on the Wikimedia Commons,
and I think if we just search
for electronic literature,
I mean category electronic literature.
We will get to a bunch of folks
that have not been identified. Yes.
So I can and it's like
person to be identified.
And once you are.
Logged in,
you can, I believe,
change the name on these folks.
And yes, I see bunches of people
and I have no clue.
So that will be fun.
Unfortunately, I don't know
if we're going to get people who are like
really familiar with the crowds or Lyle,
who knows people or not.
Ish ish is okay.
Yeah. Will at least try for that. Try?
Yeah, we'll try for that.
So we will crowdsource
some. We'll crowdsource.
So, Glenn,
if you want to share your screen.
Let's see.
And then if you want to go to that
first link that we put in. Yep.
I have it pulled up here. Cool.
And now it says create account or login.
Oh I just have to refresh.
I just logged in a few. Wonderful.
Okay.
So go perfect your wiki spew. Great.
Scroll down on this page.
Down down down. We have easier tasks.
We have folks.
Okay. Wait. Stop. Go back up.
What I where I want
you is the list of participants.
And you could actually
list of participants.
See it on the left hand side there.
Up up up up up down down down down down
down down down down there.
There there there.
There we go. Sorry.
Okay. Click edit.
See it says list of participants.
And then there's an edit.
Oh yes.
Go down to the bottom of this.
Type in.
See that last star user star for user.
And it says butchered on.
Yeah I've been a star
on the next line.
And then for a space, then for Tilda.
Okay.
Now hit list of participants
down at the bottom.
See where it says edit summary.
Yes and say added name.
Added name.
All right.
Brilliant.
Now hit publish changes.
Okay.
So that is your job
is to like on an aside with people
is to get them to do that.
Okay. You are not logged in.
Oh shoot.
This is sorry.
No worries.
The other reason to do
all of this is Wikipedia
library gets you more
scholarly journals
now, especially in the US.
I don't know where you're based,
but really now
in the US, the only way that you can get
many scholarly publications like ACM,
you know, Elsevier,
anything like that is to be on Wikipedia
for six months and make 500 edits.
You do that, you've got free access.
Not a lot of time necessary
for a lot of these things.
But yeah, you do need that.
So now are you logged in? Yes.
Do the same thing.
See, this is a test.
Yeah. So sorry.
No worries, no worries.
And now that I need
glasses to see the screen.
Right.
I got new ones.
You got new ones? Oh, they look so cool.
They changed their the special.
Like they change when I go in the sun.
I'm just.
I'm spoiled now.
Yeah, mine is mine or two now.
Which is a real pain.
But yeah.
Now let's see what you got.
Brilliant. That's fine.
Click on Wiki Spew for a second.
This is the other thing
I want you guys to do.
This is your page.
I want you to edit something here.
Just anything. It says.
Yeah, see?
It says.
Type.
Yeah.
Type in the box below who you are.
I am a grad student, I don't care.
Just give us some credibility.
Because the other reason for this,
Lyle, is
people are coming back over that list
and saying, well, you have people
that we don't know who they are
and we don't care to do not qualified.
Oh, for crying out loud.
I know, I know,
we are still working on this.
I still have the stalkers
after three years.
Jeez,
I know,
brilliant.
I'll fix the typos in a second.
It doesn't matter.
Yeah, that's. That's lovely.
Sorry.
No worries, no worries. So.
Hit publish page
on your own page.
You really don't need the edit summary,
but on anybody else's, you do.
Great. Well,
we're getting started.
The other thing that I want you to do
is go back to the Wikipedia,
our project page.
So go back to that.
Now on the side it's going to say.
Article alerts I think.
Yeah.
Click on the article alerts
I think that'll do it.
Where I want you to.
What I want you to do now is to put this
link on your user page, actually,
and I'm not quite sure where it is.
So scroll scroll up on this.
Okay.
Oh there there was user
box template is what you want.
Box template
passed it already.
You might have scroll.
Scroll down.
This page does need to get cleaned up.
Okay here we go.
Yes okay.
See that code?
Just this code at the top there. That.
Yeah, yeah, yeah. Click all that.
Copy that.
You can come down to this list of participants if you like and click on you again.
Now on your user page you are
going to edit source
see where it says read Edit Source.
Brilliant.
You're going to copy that copy.
Which one? Just exactly what you paste.
What you you're going to paste
exactly what you copy.
Sorry. Good morning.
Then you're going to just hit publish it.
Yay.
And now you can always click back.
On this page.
We have easy tasks for you.
We have editor thumbs. Life is good.
Okay.
We'll get started here
as people come in. Welcome.
Malian I'm
sorry I'm sorry I'm mangling your name.
You got it
the first time I did Malian melon mallet.
Sorry about that. And welcome, Mel.
I'm going to do a very quick spiel.
And that is, as Lilian was
just explaining, AI is here.
But what she did not explain is
she did it a little bit.
The bias is the training data.
And if I use this Wikipedia.
So basically we have to feed the beast.
Also if you feed the beast, if you become
a Wikipedia editor, we love you.
And if you do 500 edits in six months,
you get access to the Wikipedia library,
which is better than any university
library.
Particularly particularly now in the US.
You want a scholarship,
you want to read a scholarly publication.
You do not have to pay.
You will have to do this for six months.
Do you do
you and Mel have accounts on Wikipedia?
I will say Mel is our chair.
I think they might be elsewhere.
Cool beans. Okay.
And gazella to. Yay!
So we're getting folks.
Oh, we got lots more folks.
Sorry about that.
Okay, so in the chat,
you guys, would you put down
whether or not
you have a Wikipedia account?
Yay! Melon does.
Okay.
So melon.
Okay. So
let's do it this way.
Glenn, can you work directly with Gazella?
I don't think there are breakout
rooms, are there?
I think I can set up breakout rooms.
Yeah, set up a breakout room
and you and Gazella
go in there
and you teach her exactly what we did.
You know how to create an account,
right? Yes.
Teach gazella.
Cool.
Hey, Monica.
Yay! I'm glad you have.
And we've got Remi as well.
And we've got a Remi.
Okay, you guys basically
let me go back into this.
Everybody will hear this
a couple of times.
Wikipedia is important to feed AI.
We don't get into Wikipedia.
We don't get into things
like notable project,
which I just found out
about, which is kind of cool.
I just
found out about notable people yesterday,
but it runs on Wikipedia.
There's a lot of things that do.
So what we have to do is feed the beast.
If you do not have an account yet,
put your name.
Well, if you have an account or not,
put your status of account
in Wikipedia in the chats.
And Glenn is going to teach you
how to log in
and how to get into our Wikipedia project
in that breakout room.
If you do have an account,
yeah,
we'll walk you through it, no problem.
And it is so important to have six months,
500 edits.
You get access to the world
of scholarly publications.
And more importantly for me, we are trying
to develop notability guidelines.
We have been said, oh, well, it's
not notable cause it's not in print.
God, you guys okay?
But unfortunately I need 100 people
to sign up on our project
and be active editors
in order to put forward
the notability guidelines that we want,
because we have to follow their rules.
Life is fun.
So as we're doing this, I don't see
too many folks in the chat
saying all this stuff.
Monica, you've got an
you've got an account.
I'm finding it,
I'm finding it, you're finding it.
It's somewhere.
Yeah.
And it's much better to find your
old account than to create a new account,
because then if you have two accounts,
they consider you to be a sock puppet.
And they don't like you very much.
Hey, John, you are a co-host.
Lovely.
You're probably not even here.
I am here you are here.
Do you have a Wikipedia account? No.
Okay.
We missed John out in our crusade.
How did we do that?
Oh my God. Hi, Michael.
So I avoid the crusade.
Okay.
There
you go. Please don't avoid the crusade.
We need your knowledge.
Yeah, we really need white dudes.
For something.
That is another thing.
Lyle and I started this because 80%,
we have now progressed to only 80%
of the men of the editors are men.
We have
we have gained like 12% or something.
So we really are doing the Women's
Electronic Literature project.
We are still working
to really get women in the field,
and we have made a lot of progress.
But for this one, I have
you guys as experts in two ways
Wikipedia and electronic literature.
So Michael, em and others,
if you have not gotten an account,
get into the breakout room with Glenn.
Is there the breakout rooms now?
Yeah, yeah, you should be able
to. There's just one room.
You should be able to pull it up
under more?
Yeah. Under more.
I don't see anybody has joined there.
But if you do not have
an account like Sela doesn't
go into
that breakout
room and Glenn will help you out.
And then
those of you who have an account,
I'm going to start sharing my screen,
because what we're going to do with
this is help Dina out because she is face
blind.
I have no idea who people are.
And last year we took a bunch of pictures
and I promptly lost the papers.
So OPD is here.
Oh, wonderful.
If you have an account
you can come to
and I will put this in here.
Our Wikipedia page.
And we are going to put in the names
of who
these people are if you know them.
So pretty much go to this URL.
It's in the chat and tell
me if you know anybody here.
Does anybody
recognize any of these people?
The dark green shirt that you passed
I think is Stuart Mothra.
Yeah, I think it's that Stuart.
It's very, very small.
Oh, it's very small.
Yeah.
Does that help? Yes.
Okay.
This is a person to be identified.
So we click on the person
to be identified.
It is much bigger.
We think this is Stuart Rob. Yeah.
Especially since his name tag says Stuart
Mothra.
It doesn't.
Even pleasing.
Amazing.
So now what I have to do is the last
is for the win.
I did not have glasses for the win.
And now I have to remember how to do this.
You go into edit and rather than person
to be identified.
We changed this somehow.
At the very least,
we note that it's Stuart up here
and then I can figure it out later.
But we.
Have a
category we can actually kind of do.
Stuart.
Most Rob
I think sure I'd forgotten how to do this.
And then we can just say this is Stuart.
And at the very least do this guys.
And we can figure it out later.
I'm going to watch this page
because when I do that, somebody
if I see it, I can change it.
And there are like
folks so I can somehow change this.
Oh okay.
I can at least edit the caption.
So I'm going to go Stuart
Mall Thrupp at okay.
And then I'm going to ask
folks let's just edit captions right now.
And then we can do that.
So okay so next.
So do you guys see how to do this.
Probably not because I was confused
I don't know actually how to do this. So
do we know anybody else.
There you are.
I think that's you. Me?
Yes, yes.
You weren't that dress last year.
Yeah, that's definitely you. Yes.
No, sir.
Actually, I don't know if I.
Oh, I know I can't do this one, so
somebody else is going to have to do this.
Oh, yeah. My guy.
And yes,
you can.
Yeah.
And number three.
So and so.
Yeah. You can't even see this.
Why weren't you wearing a name tag.
So what we're going to do is edit
the description.
I'm not sure how to edit
the actual name of the file.
So if somebody can figure that out
that would be lovely.
So this is p d Edgar and Monarch.
Now you're testing
stories like RSS feed
okay.
So at least we have this one.
Thank you guys.
And if you guys figure out
how to edit the name of the file,
that would be amazing.
I do not look for that right now.
Brilliant.
Okay, so and everybody who does not have
an account is probably in Glenn's room.
I'm just going to check on our.
Well, I was going to say
everybody who needs to make an account.
I sent the link out
a couple of seconds ago.
If you run to any issues, we can all just
go into that breakout room.
If anybody needs guidance,
that's a good idea.
So somebody could like, this is me.
Oh, yeah, that's my pinwheel.
So somebody, like, can fix me.
And do we know any of these people?
Yes. Oh, wait. No, no.
It's this Jason Nelson.
Yeah. No. Yes.
This is Jason Nelson. Okay.
I feel like I'm face blind now.
No, don't be
my trouble.
I'm named doom in he.
They got a.
I don't think that's Jason.
Oh, you don't think that's Jason?
Zoom in on zoom into the.
No, I don't think that is. You're right.
I don't think there.
We just saw long hair and went,
Jason Nelson.
Yeah, I spoke to the Perth
and I can't remember their name.
Oh I can't.
Let's
see if I can even see in on their name
tag. No.
Okay.
Fair enough.
Hold on, hold on, hold on, hold on.
Oh, don't. Don't move anything.
I almost had no move.
Nothing.
Okay.
I think I know who that is.
Who is this?
No, not like clarifying for me.
Just don't move. Chris Arnold.
Chris Arnold. Yeah.
Okay.
So Chris Arnold. So. Okay,
I feel like when I, I mean,
it's enhancing
and I feel like I'm in a minority report
or something where I can just go
enhance, enhance, enhance.
The other reason to do
these is to connect them to Wikidata.
And I'm not sure how to do that either.
I didn't look it up for this meeting,
but at least we have names.
So all of you guys can go on to this page
and you can start zooming as well.
Or you can look at this one and
I can kind of make them bigger I think.
Is this better?
I think that's my dress. Yes.
Yeah.
You know what this is. No.
So somebody else is going to have to do
this.
Never ever. Even on photos edit your own.
He was the gallery manager
for York, I think. Oh,
Ellen Lou I think.
Yeah.
So somebody put that in.
Okay.
Because this one I can't do he can
probably go back to ELO 2025 and find his.
Yes. Thank you.
Joel Ong, this is Joel Ong right here.
No, the the guy with you in the pic
is, That's not Joel.
That's his grad student.
Right? PT
let me see the exhibitions.
Who was the. So.
Yeah. And you got.
I don't even know where that guy went.
Raiders were.
I can probably I lost it.
Sorry.
This is a big mess.
We will not do it this way again.
We have learned.
I'm so sorry.
But. Okay, we did that one.
I have a feeling this is Holly Slocum,
because I know the next museum,
but I'm not sure you guys think so?
Yes, I met with her that day, I think.
Yeah, that kind of looked.
Well, I remember the exhibit,
and I know Holly has long, black
brown hair.
This was so bad.
This is why I needed you guys here.
Okay?
So what I would do is. And edit
this and go.
I know how to spell Holly.
And the next exhibit at the.
Okay.
Oh, and as you do these, watch the page.
Because that way. Okay.
If you can.
Well remember who who has what
and I will try and work on these
again.
We want to the next
step is to connect these to Wikidata.
And Lyle is desperately trying
to figure out how to do that.
Yes, yes. Thank you.
Is this guy John McDaid?
I kind of know.
Maybe not know. This is not
John McDade, is it?
It is.
It is John McDaid.
We have John McDaid here.
Okay, cool.
That's not me.
Is it?
No idea who this is.
I know that's my pinwheel.
God knows why Dini likes the pinwheel.
The pinwheel is a
is a physical hypertext
that Dini likes that I did,
when we go into edit
one of the images, are we editing the file
name or are we editing?
I would love to edit the file name. Yes.
I don't know how to do that. John.
If you want to share posted the link
you go to tool.
So when you're on the editing page
a while, you share
okay.
Oh I need to request sharing
because I'm not a
oh how do you request sharing okay
Glenn can Glenn can help me share.
Yeah I can assign it.
And we do have more folks coming in now
I can share.
And, Carol just came in.
Carol let us know in the chat
if you have a Wikipedia.
Account.
Okay.
So when you.
So over here if you're on the editing page
for the image.
Yeah.
Over here under tools and it may.
If it's on appearance
it may hide everything.
So you gotta make sure you have tools.
You click on move.
And then it actually gives you
the instructions.
While it loads.
Yeah.
Because our goal
is to like rename all of these.
And if we have something
in. If when
the next time we do this in person
we will set this up much better.
So we were the file
names are usually the file names.
Them has like with spaces
with middle names.
I feel like if you're going to use,
if you're going to ask everyone
to rename the files,
should I think
as long as the person's name is in them?
Yes, it would be good to have a schema,
but at the moment, as long as we name
the person and we're fine,
that's what's missing.
So the idea is that
if someone were to download that file,
at least the name
would be attached to the downloaded file.
Yeah, exactly.
And now that you have created your name,
the very first thing that we want
you to do is to sign in
under Wikipedia,
WP lit.
And Glenn, can you help do that
in the chat or.
Yeah, of these reasons
are going to fall under
number two,
a meaningless or ambiguous name.
So we're changing them
from unidentified person to
identified something.
Do they want citations
like their faculty profiles or anything?
Yes. Anything that you can add here
would be fantastic.
And we're also going to connect it
to Wikidata.
But anything you've got put it in.
And Carol, the reason
why you want to be a Wikipedia,
you want to have a Wikipedia account
in several fold.
One is to help us out in the Wikipedia
project
that we have for electronic literature.
The other is very selfish.
If you're on for six months
and you do 500 edits,
which actually, honestly isn't that hard,
we have got lots of easy edits.
There's ways to do this.
You will then get access
to all of the scholarly articles, and
I happen to know that you are not
a faculty member at a university,
so this would really help you out.
So like
exactly.
So Lyle has renamed this person to be Mark
sample.
It's a request.
So you can't we can't do it ourselves.
We can't put it in a request.
So if you see now once I've done that form
now has a rename request.
Okay.
Cool.
All the rationale for and who did it
and all of that.
Let's go ahead and then edit
the description and say Mark sample.
Yeah.
So that at least mark sample gets in.
There is a 50.
Yeah.
And Glenn is inviting everybody
who does not have a Wikipedia account
to join the breakout room.
Please.
You only have the one breakout room.
And Glenn will be so nice and help
you get an account and sign in. Yes.
And even for getting them started on
becoming a participant of the project.
I can get you started there too. Oh, good.
And if you've never been to an electronic
literature
conference, that's cool.
We can help.
Go to the WP lit page, try for the easy
edits and let us know how that works.
What we're doing
is because I am extremely face blind.
I do not even recognize my own mother.
We are going through these pages
trying to see who people are.
So now that we know how to do that.
Shall I share again?
And like drive or does people do
people know what they do?
Take the wheel.
I will take the wheel.
Okay.
Basically,
if you know of any of these people,
if you can see them shut out
who the hell they are.
Because unfortunately we took all these
pictures and I don't know who they are.
Who that who. Scroll up. Black shirt.
Monica Monica Brown one down, one down.
Not not the blue shirt. That's me.
That's Monica.
Yeah. Oh, cool.
Okay, so now what I will do is edit
this and let's see
if I absorbed Lyle's information.
I'm going to go over to tools
and I'm going to
move again. Lyle
you're going to move.
Yep. Okay.
And then I get this and I'm going
to get into the new name.
And let's see if I remember how to spell
Monica source.
So you guys can start doing
these on your own as well.
And you can do these at any time.
By the way, I started editing myself
and I'm pretty sure.
So when you read
yeah, edit the file name that,
you know, it's just like a request.
I'm pretty sure it shows on the page that
someone else has already submitted that.
So that way just keep an eye out for that
so that we don't like people
changing the same one.
Never ever.
Oh you did this one okay.
And I think so.
Yeah.
If you oh if you've done this one
and you're not Monica.
If we request renaming that's cool.
A couple of times is not a problem.
That's why
like in fact
that might get us even more people. But.
Yeah.
So okay, I was also trying to.
And did you edit them the.
No. Okay.
So I'm just trying to also edit
the caption so that we don't lose
the information.
Yeah.
Oh, and it says it's been suggested.
So if we if you've already edited it then
this it's been suggested should show up.
And we can skip that one.
We have no idea
who these people are.
Wait.
That is that's a Kaitlyn Fisher.
That's Caitlin Fisher.
Cool.
So I will come into
move.
I will say, let's see if I can remember.
And, you know, we could keep it at ELO
2025 is fine.
But just make sure you have that name in.
I think I've spelled Caitlin's name right.
Yes, yes.
Okay. And then I can just say Request
Club and I can change.
I want to make sure
that I change the caption
caption. Go.
So it says Kate and Fisher.
Okay, somebody has tried to do this,
but we didn't get it
moved from the person to be identified.
Cool.
We have no idea.
Who these people are.
As you go through.
That's Mark Marino, that's Mark
Marino I thought I was recognized the hat.
Yay! So.
And I suppose you guys are doing this
on your own as well.
Yeah.
So a couple of people
need to be added to
we need to have them
add themselves to the project.
So do we want to let the folks who know
how to do the imaging start on that,
and then get John and caught up
on adding themselves to the project?
Or do you want me to pop into the breakout
room with them?
Pop into the breakout room?
Sure to add to the project?
And I see that somebody added this one.
So yeah, we we somebody has asked for
this one to be redone.
I have to make this a little bit smaller
so I can see what I'm doing.
Hold on. Scroll up. Yeah.
No, they haven't asked for the file
to be renamed.
They've just added him
into the description.
So we really do need to ask that this.
Yeah.
Right.
Yeah,
that'd be nice.
Yeah.
So request
renaming is really kind of important.
So. Yes.
And please add yourself to the WP project.
We need to get to 100 people,
add your students,
add anybody and go to the breakout room.
And Lyle will show you how to do that
okay.
So now I've got this one
and we should be adding.
We should be adding a note
on published changes.
You should always add a note
on publish changes.
Because what happens
is you get a view history that says hey
we should rename this.
So yeah.
I don't know what happened.
Okay.
All right.
So we have Mark named yay,
by the way.
We have I think about 300 of these photos.
So if you can hit load more
and there's a description tag in them
that we can edit as well.
You said yes.
Okay, I believe so. So.
Where did mine go?
If you recognize any of these others,
that would be great to.
I'm thinking that we can search on person
to be identified.
Was our like how did this work?
Okay. Yeah.
Hang on.
I've lost myself.
Sorry about this.
Okay, so if you search also
just on the Wiki Commons
main page, which was where I had been,
and if you search
up here.
There should be a search engine.
Really?
There should be. Just a second.
I'm seeing it too big.
It's my problem. And I'm only on a laptop.
There it is.
Search Wikimedia Commons
electronic literature
person to be identified
or just even person.
And that will probably
yes, get you this list of people
that we just said
person that needs to be identified.
Do we know any of these people?
You know, I'm going to link you to one
that has both me and Monica
and at the augmented reality
Poetry Machine, but we can't edit that.
We're in it. Right?
Put that link in the chat
and then we can do that.
So we don't know who this is.
I just renamed that one.
That's Kathy Behrens.
Thank you.
And the green shirt guy was Stuart.
This one I think we lost somebody's head.
But I think if you click on it
I might be John.
That is John.
Did we link to John. No.
We got person to be identified.
So we need to get
Jonathan Murray in here.
That that is huge on.
Right.
He might be in the breakout room.
Oh cool.
Okay so this is but this is John Murray.
So it's
move and then it's John Murray okay
I'm learning how to do this.
And then I can edit this I think.
So I was just editing the description.
John's got an A in his name right.
So yeah.
And then just saying.
Identify as John Murray.
Brilliant.
And now all of you know
the next time you see me in person
you have to identify yourself
because otherwise
get it.
Being first blinded.
So much fun.
Do we know who
the guy in the yellow shirt is?
Oh, maybe.
I can click on him.
It's Andrew.
Oh, and we have him. Okay.
So yeah.
So apparently two
people have been doing this
but we haven't been saying to move them.
So anytime you see one of these
guys who do have a name, yay!
We simply
move them.
Did anybody do John's on the wiki media?
I don't know.
Should do I have to do this this way?
So tools.
Why my tools isn't showing up.
Interesting.
I do have Andrew here
I can request.
Need to
rename.
This guy.
For some reason I'm not seeing move
in what I can do.
And maybe I can rename this.
Oh, it's been suggested.
So somebody already did this. Great.
Okay, so yeah,
I just need to look below to
you can't do moves
if somebody already suggested it.
Yeah. Thank you.
13 whoever you are.
So did we do John's
I can check because if we had done John's.
This is John Murray.
No, that one's Monica stores
and PD Edgar
at the augmented reality poetry machine.
Oh, okay. Sorry.
Thank you.
So I can change the caption.
I should look at this augmented
reality, our reality poetry machine.
And you can put a lot of information
into the caption.
And I guess
we would want to rename this one.
Oh, okay, fine.
Rename them anywhere you can.
What was it again?
Is one able to put links
into the descriptions like weekly links?
Sort of.
I'm not sure, but I think so.
What you could do
is if you can't,
there's also a discussion page.
So you can say, how do I do that?
And if you are, if you find your own,
you can say,
please rename this to me
in the discussion.
Never touch your own stuff.
And then you can always watch the page.
Yes, we have made.
We are making huge, huge strides.
Whoops. Maybe.
Is I can get
there again if I search on.
We have these in the category
electronic literature.
So we do have a category.
And if it just says electronic literature
person, that means we have no idea
who these people are.
Or at least they have.
They still have person in their names.
So. I remember
oh well okay, that doesn't help much.
No idea.
That's such a style.
Sasha.
Yeah, that's Sasha.
Okay.
So this is Sasha Styles. Yep.
How do you spell her last name?
Do you know
I l e s?
It's perfectly okay.
As Leo was saying,
to have different naming conventions,
but because people just will,
at the very least, we'd have them.
I think I've just been following
the standard,
like first name, space, last name.
I think that was the example I'll used.
Yeah, I think that works really well.
Yay, we got one.
I think there's like 300.
The other thing that we can do
is you guys don't know
who it is, what we could start doing.
Like we decided we knew who that person
is, but we don't know who this person is.
We could start
a missing person's on the discord.
Okay. But also helps.
So if we go on to discord and go,
hopefully I get to electronic literature.
Where did my electronic literature go to?
I know how to do this, really, I don't.
I had it up a moment ago,
but if somebody would like go to discord
and start putting these in,
that would there we go.
Electronic literature.
That didn't help.
There it goes.
Like if can we make a new discussion?
Let me see if I have a permissions
to start a new.
Yeah.
And then we could just like start
copying and going, who the hell is this?
And kind of crowd mind.
That will help a great deal.
So yeah.
Thank you John okay.
Oh brilliant.
So if I go into discussion
I might be able to PD.
Sorry.
Thank you PD yay. Yeah you're good.
So it's where down here in 2026.
Go back up.
We'll go back up. Yeah.
Right under General Conference
we can say hi.
We need to identify.
These folks.
Yeah.
That's a much better way to say it.
How is this.
Right.
So if you don't know
you can just start grabbing people.
And if we have it twice, that's cool too.
Did we decide we knew who this person was?
Yes. That's Andrew Demetri.
Oh, we did that okay.
Yeah. You're right.
We did the yellow guy. Yep.
And this is how editing works,
by the way.
Every edit that you make gets to your 500.
So there you go.
Wash it again.
And. We decided
we didn't know who curly haired was.
Right.
We don't know who that is.
On these should we like
I think just maybe it's
easier on the discord
to ask people to put it there.
Do you think like that or
drag them through the Wikipedia?
I think it's easier to do this. Maybe.
No it's not.
No it's not,
because then we have to, like, find them.
So let's not do that.
Let's go ahead and put in the actual URL
in the discord.
That would make life a lot better, because
then otherwise I'm looking for a photo.
So is there a
way PD to like reply to this?
And how do I do
the reply in the thread
to those specific things?
Okay,
so like if I wanted to reply to the exit,
the upper right, the exit
the upper right, great.
Now right click it the the background,
not the picture,
but I think you'd also click there.
Yeah. Reply.
Yep okay.
This is on this page.
And have I done that correctly.
Yes. Okay.
So this person is this page
because they have a plaid shirt. Yay.
Okay.
Then the other one I screwed up on right.
Have too many things open.
The other guy that we were looking for
was this guy.
White shirt, curly hair.
This is like at an airport.
You know, if you have the white shirt
and the curly hair, please reply.
So I click on this.
Yeah. No, I don't do that.
I come back, I click on the background
and I hit reply and go, this unknown
person is at here.
Yes. So.
Brilliant.
Okay. Yeah.
Let's go ahead and put the
this unknown person as at.
Yeah.
Actually you could just put the URL right
and not the picture.
That might be easier
and go, okay,
whatever I put in the media.
Yeah okay.
Fair enough.
Okay.
That's not it.
Can I ask a question?
How do you,
while we're being human, flock cameras.
How do we know that
these people want to be identified?
Oh, because that can come.
I can reply to this one with the photo
because I want the photo
and the URL at the same place. Yes.
That works.
So striped shirt guy
and striped shirt guy.
Who'd be here?
Okay.
Yeah.
So I don't know how much time we've got.
One minutes.
Okay. So.
And everybody on the call
I'm going to stop sharing for a moment.
But everybody on the call
kind of sees how to do this.
Yeah.
Brilliant.
Now that I have 15 minutes we do editor.
We do an editing
actually pretty much tomorrow.
And this could be helpful.
Oh thank you.
The directory of speakers
could be very helpful
because we can spell their names right.
But basically why we're doing this is
several fold.
One is we got to feed the beast.
We have Wikipedia feeds, AI feeds, notable
people, feeds a lot of things.
Nowadays we need to be in Wikipedia.
When you go into Google
and you search on anybody
or search on electronic literature,
the very first thing that shows up
is the Wikipedia.
Because Wikipedia and Google
have a lovely agreement right now.
AI same thing, ChatGPT same thing.
So we need to feed the beast.
We need to be editing Wikipedia.
Otherwise
anything about electronic literature is
just going to be squelched
in our new information age.
Okay, Wikipedia has really interesting
search algorithms and they if you have a
image,
they put you up higher in the search.
So images on our Wikipedia
pages are extremely important.
So this first step is to actually
identify our images that we have.
The second step is
then to take these images that we now have
and put them to the proper Wikidata
and Wikipedia article.
Once we get that, then
we can get higher in the ratings.
We we can do the search
engine option optimization.
I personally, like I said on Facebook, and
I have no idea why people care about what
people look like, but apparently they do.
So, you know,
we have to go with the NT biases here.
Neurotypical biases.
Fine.
We just play their game.
But again, Wikipedia is critical
for developing our Wikipedia databases.
If if you guys have classes
and you teach writing, kind of like
what Lillian was talking about a bit
in the keynote,
it's important now to address
and to incorporate the AI,
but if you want to have an assignment
where you're making sure that the students
are writing in human language
as much as possible,
assign them a assign them Wikipedia.
Wikipedia is
committed now to running by human
editors rather than AI editors,
and they're working on that.
It's kind of a race war, but
every sentence in a Wikipedia
article has to be referenced.
So when you have students
who are writing or editing,
they are then developing the skills
of looking
at an article in a newspaper
or a research study
summarizing it
and putting that reference into Wikipedia.
It's an incredibly valuable
skill being an being
a wiki, having Wikipedia editor
on your resume as a student
is actually really helpful
for for employers.
So it says, hey,
this person knows how to write.
They're not just filling in something.
So I'm happy to help
with any class that you have.
If you want to do this as extra credit
for classes, that helps a great deal.
I'll share my screen for just a moment,
as we have five minutes left
and show you what I mean here.
So if you go into Google, for example,
you come over here
and you say electronic literature.
What the hell is it?
You're going to get what Joe
Walker and I wrote.
Really? We are,
that goes into Wikipedia.
All of this is is from Wikipedia.
Almost straight on.
We now have a lot
in electronic literature.
Before Lyle and Jill
and I started this project,
there was like,
I don't know, 3 or 400 words in here.
That was it.
It was not, well, well developed.
But we also now have
lists of electronic
literature writers and critics.
We have so many.
We have done a lot of work.
Let me tell you,
we also have a women's one.
This list is human created.
We also have a parallel
category system now.
Yay of electronic literature writers
and they are by type of writer.
And we have people putting people up
and they are by country
and by and by format.
So we have a lot of sub subcategories.
An easy task is to help
help us with the categories.
But you see how we're working on this
and you see how much work
we still need to do.
So join us every third Thursday.
Email me I will put
I know this is a silly address
for me to have, but it's kind of ironic.
I have just put my email in the chat.
Anytime you want to work on Wikipedia,
let me know.
I'm happy to help.
If you see something that's going on
with your particular article,
do not edit this.
Let me know.
And we will figure it out.
But when Lyle and I first started,
I think we had what Lyle,
15 or 20 articles on women,
electronic literature writers,
something like that.
If that, if that, if that.
Yeah.
I mean, 20 would be like the outside.
And now look what we've done.
Yeah that's exciting.
It is so exciting.
And we are working on a spreadsheet
and I will put that in as well.
That does need to be updated but.
Com slash w e w spread.
So we do have this spreadsheet.
Tiny URL
spread that shows the.
Status of articles,
whether they're completed,
whether they need an image
which is where we like
we're talking about.
So this kind of goes back
to if you know these people.
We need an image.
And what you're doing right now
will help a great deal.
We need edits
because these articles are ones
that have popped up going, hey,
you got a problem.
So there is a lot of work that we need.
Spreadsheet.
It is a slick spreadsheet.
Yeah, we still need to update it,
but yeah.
So please join in.
Please help us to research to right.
We have some research going on
where we need to write it.
So please help out writing
articles, editing
articles, whatever you can do.
And again yay!
Tell your students,
especially as they leave the university.
Six months, 500 edits
and you get the Wikipedia library,
which is pretty.
I can as a as an independent scholar,
I can tell you
this is like changed my life.
It really has,
I now have I can log in via Wikipedia
because I have the six months and
the 500 edits, and this is what you get.
I can everything from ACM Digital Library.
I mean,
Africa Intelligence
is kind of a critical thing right now.
We're also working on different Wikipedias
translators.
If you could work with your university
and say, hey,
does anybody need a language assignment,
let us know.
We can help with that.
Bristol University Press British newspaper
article archive
I mean, and I'm only in the bees.
There's a lot of stuff here.
Oh go ahead.
What is Wikipedia's
take on using like proceedings
and the like actual conference
programs and stuff
like that as, as sources
like if I was going to update Sasha's page
to say that she gave our keynote
and I can like link in the photo of that.
Yes. Like, do they count like the schedule
from the conference where she,
like is listed as a reliable source?
Or do they want like a published document
text?
Yes, both.
They will take the they will take that
URL as a reliable source.
It would be really great
when we have the public
the proceedings on a URL,
they'll take that.
And that is the other reason
underlying why we want 100 people
to be on that Wikipedia page,
because Jill Walker and I
and others have developed a notability
guideline just for us.
And on that notability guidelines,
we want to say, hey,
these conference proceedings are gold.
They count.
So there's a lot of political stuff
going on behind the scenes there.
But yes,
anything you guys can do for this
we still need.
We've we've gone a long ways. Yay.
But we need to do a lot more.
I see we have two more minutes.
Any other questions
have I gave you into being Wikipedia
editors who?
Not for me, but I'm emailing you now
just to follow up on this.
Thanks so much for this workshop. Sure.
And thank you for following up.
And yeah, any students that you have,
anybody we can we can pull into this.
I am happy to help.
I will say the only thing is
I'll say to check your spam
because it's been happening
with my email lately.
Often goes to spam.
Yeah, your email goes to spam.
Oh, lovely.
Sadly,
I follow all the protocols that they need
on the Amex designations or whatever,
but specifically,
Gmail seems to not like me.
Oh dear. I'm on proton.
I like proton a lot.
Yeah, it's been happening to me
with proton.
I've recently switched over to Tuta
because I've been very disappointed
with Proton's political commitments.
But yeah,
it's.
I don't see you.
Yeah. I didn't get it.
I would
it sent about a couple seconds ago.
It's just me at one Ritchie.
Me at Glenn.
Ritchie.
Okay.
Oh, I think I got it.
Yay! Yes.
And continue your involvement
beyond this workshop.
Yeah. We need you, Glenn.
We will. I will email you.
Hey, here's how to get involved.
And by the way, one last second,
email me and tell me
that you want to be on the second Tuesday
salons
because we do very fun stuff
on that every second Tuesday.
And we also have the third Thursday.
So I will I will add you.